翻译：草草  CS漫画家小明  鱼小姐  香茗小焙
翻译：王大可  某羽   校对：某羽  油炸电风扇
时间轴：若林   act206
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第四季   第十一集
翻译：草草  CS漫画家小明  菲力  杨一勾
翻译：木浅薰  某羽  小饭   校对：某羽
时间轴：包包  kallen  小式
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第四季   第十四集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on Suits
迈克·罗斯从没上过法学院
Mike Ross never went to law school.
我知道  但我还是雇了他
I knew it, and I hired him anyway.
我还是不能留下来  哈维
I still can't stay, Harvey.
我知道
I know.
我只是不想再欺骗我爱的人了
I just want to stop lying to the people I love.
这份文件会表明傅滋曼的付款
This makes it look like Forstman's payment never
从未经过任何离岸账户
went to any offshore accounts.
这可是伪造
That's forgery.
那也比你犯下的罪行要轻
Which is less of a crime than what you did.
我没得选
I had no choice!
去你的没得选
Bullshit, you had no choice!
你可以在任何一个时点上说不
You could've said no at any goddamn point along the way.
有一件事是板上定钉的
One thing is for sure.
当一切结束之后  我会把你炒掉
When all this is over, I'm gonna fire the shit out of you.
我去找了罗伯特·赞恩
I went to Robert Zane
要他给路易一个职位
and I asked him to give Louis a job.
你想看看我能不能打破自己的合伙契约是吧
You want to see if I can break my partnership agreement?
假如你连这个都做不到
If you can't do that,
那你还算什么厉害人物
what the hell good are you?
路易不会去赞恩那里
Louis won't be going to Zane,
你也不会了
and neither will you.
我来请求你无论如何雇下路易
I'm here to ask you to take Louis anyway.
我为什么要雇他
And why would I do that?
你雇下他  我就欠你份情
If you do it, I'll owe you one.
迈克·罗斯过目不忘
Mike Ross doesn't forget anything.
他认不出这钥匙的原因
See, the reason he didn't recognize this
是因为他没上过哈佛
was because he didn't go to Harvard.
你从迈克·罗斯来的第一天就开始骗我
You've been lying to me since the day Mike Ross arrived.
-我是你朋友啊  路易  -不  你不是
- I am your friend, Louis. - No, you're not.
你再也不准对我说那样的话
And don't you ever say that to me again.
你还是直接说吧
So you might as well spit it out.
你曾经问过我想要什么  我告诉了你
You asked me what I wanted once before and I told you.
那时你说我不可能得到
And then you tole me I couldn't have it.
皮尔逊
Pearson.
斯佩克特
Specter
利特
Litt.
什么事那么重要
Want to tell me what was so important
还把我叫回来了
I had to get back here?
他知道了
He knows.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
唐娜怎么没告诉你
Why didn't Donna tell you?
我告诉你吧
I'll tell you why.
因为作为冠名合伙人  我的第一项命令
Because as my first official act as name as name partner,
就是叫她别告诉你
I told her not to.
什么
What?
没错
You heard me.
你爱盯着她看多久都行
You can look at her as long as you want.
她帮不了你
She can't help you.
因为我的名字明天一早就要挂上去
Because my name's going up there first thing tomorrow.
别做梦了
No, it isn't.
他没说错
Yes, it is.
但不能明天就做
But it won't be tomorrow.
我不能等着你...
I'm not waiting just so you can--
路易  我得给资深合伙人一个说得过去的理由
Louis, I have to sell this to the senior partners.
我不能突然就把你的名字甩上去
I can't just slap your name up there one morning.
你为他那么做过
You did it for him.
我可没在前一周辞职
I didn't resign the week before.
-我不管  -路易
- I don't care. - Louis.
够了
That's enough.
这事得慢慢来
This is going to take time,
在此期间  你不能对外透露情况
and while it does, you're going to keep this to yourself.
胡扯  你就是在争取时间  想摆脱困境
Bullshit. You're just trying to buy time so you can get out of this.
我没想争取什么
I'm not trying to buy anything.
我们已经说好了  这是为你好
We have an agreement, and this is for your own good.
那为了你好
Well, for your own good,
你最好记住如果让我等太久  我会做出什么事
you better remember what I'll do if this takes too long.
告诉我你是没有别的办法
Please tell me you had no other choice.
你很清楚我是没有
You know damn well I didn't.
我不清楚
No, I don't.
那是你没看见他的样子
That's because you didn't see him.
他自出生那一天起  就一直渴望
All he's ever thought about since the day he was born
得到这个
was getting this.
如果我要在满足他的心愿
So if I have to choose between giving it to him
和坐牢之间做选择
and going to jail--
他真威胁你了吗
He really threatened that?
他不止是威胁我
He didn't just threaten it.
他真打算那么做
He was going to do it.
那我们要怎么办
And what are we going to do?
我们要接受
We're going to take it.
我们满足他这要求  以后会有没完的要求
We give him this, it is never gonna end.
哈维  你再开口之前
Harvey, before you say another word to me,
好好想想
I want you to think about the fact
我刚刚咽下了多大的委屈
that I just ate a big bowl of shit
只因为你把那小子招进了我的律所
because you brought that kid into my house.
但我只能接受
And I had to take it,
所以你也得接受
so you're going to take it.
哈维
Harvey.
你不用说了
You don't need to say it.
我得说
Yeah, I do.
路易来找你  我不知道该怎么办
Louis came looking for you, and I didn't know what to do.
他本打算告诉希拉一切
He was gonna call Sheila and tell her everything.
我从没见过他那副样子
I'd never seen him like that before.
唐娜  这事不怪你
Donna, this is not on you.
就是怪我
Yes, it is.
他逼问我  我崩溃了
He pressed me, and I broke.
那无所谓  他已经知道了
It doesn't matter, because he already knew.
你怎么知道
How can you know that?
因为我了解路易和你
Because I know Louis, and I know you.
如果不是已经知道了事实
And he couldn't have broken you
他不可能逼得你崩溃的
unless he knew the truth already.
所以这不怪你
So this is not your fault,
你再也别说这话了
and I never want to hear you say that again.
我至少该在你回来之前提醒你一下
I should've at least warned you before you got here.
那只会更加激怒他
All that would have done was antagonize him even more
他会知道是你说的
because he would've known you did it.
你已经尽全力了
You did everything you could've done.
好吧
Okay.
我们得告诉迈克
We have to tell Mike.
不  现在先别说
No, we don't. Not now.
哈维
Harvey.
我明早告诉他
Look, I'll tell him in the morning.
我们刚刚打赢一场大仗
We just had a huge win,
我不想把他今晚毁掉
and I am not in the mood to ruin his night.
路易
Louis.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
他们还没告诉你
They didn't tell you.
告诉我什么
Tell me what?
杰西卡让我做冠名合伙人了
Jessica made me name partner.
但是...
But, uh--
但是  但是
But? But?
但是什么
But what?
我之前引咎辞职了吗
I resigned in shame?
情况完全改变了  多亏了你
Well, that's all changed, and it's all because of you.
记得这个吗
Remember this?
不  你不记得
No, you don't,
因为你不可能记得没见过的东西
because you can't remember something you never knew.
到死都这么冷静
Cool to the end.
无所谓了  唐娜已经说了
Well, it doesn't matter, because Donna told me.
还有哈维
And Harvey.
还有杰西卡
And Jessica.
我告诉他们  我知道你是个冒牌货时
When I told them that I knew you were a fraud,
他们就像躲瘟疫一样躲着你
did they run from you like you were the plague.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
我已经得到我想要的了
I already got what I wanted from you.
-冠名合伙人  -你还有别的目的
- Name partner. - You must want something else.
否则你不会来我这儿
Otherwise, you wouldn't be here.
这就是我喜欢你的地方  迈克
See, that's what I love about you, Mike.
几乎总是先人一步
Almost always a step ahead.
我想要的
What I want from you
是你在我的律所毫无前途
is to know that you're dead at my law firm.
你不能解雇我
You can't fire me.
我为什么要解雇你  我可以击溃你
Why would I fire you when I can break you?
我要把你埋在一大堆破烂底下
You see, I'm going to bury you under a mountain of shit so big
你会求我把它挪走
you're going to be begging me to take it off.
你到时候只要说三个简单的字就行
And all you have to do is say two simple words--
就是你放任我对哈维和杰西卡
the same two words that you let me say
说的那三个字
to Harvey and Jessica.
"我辞职"
"I resign."
路易
Louis.
-你怎么来了  -我要走了
- What are you doing here? - Leaving.
这样我就不用看着你们两个骗子了
That way I don't have to look at either one of you two liars.
天呐  他知道了
Oh, my God, he knows.
他不仅知道了
He doesn't just know.
还成了冠名合伙人
He's a name partner.
-你知道了  -对  我知道了
- You know. - Yeah, I know.
你怎么不提醒我一下
And a little heads up would've been nice.
我想让你最后舒服一晚
I wanted to give you the night.
我这晚是没舒服成
Well, the night kind of got blown up
因为路易跑来我公寓
when Louis showed up at my apartment
说他要击溃我
and said he was gonna break me.
你找我干什么  迈克
What do you want from me, Mike?
我想问你怎么会让他当上了冠名合伙人
I want to know how you let him become name partner.
难道你更希望我们让他去报警吗
Would you rather we let him go to the police?
得了  我才不信路易真会去报警呢
Come on. I don't believe that Louis would actually go to the police.
杰西卡说他会他就会
He would because Jessica said he would.
所以如果你来是为了告诉我
So if you're here to say
我们可以想办法挽回这一切
that we can figure some way out of it,
那是不可能了
that's not going to happen.
他知道了  木已成舟
He knows, and it's done.
你没听到我的话吗
Did you hear what I said?
路易怒火朝天地跑到我公寓来
Louis came to my apartment filled with rage,
告诉我他会一门心思
and he told me he was making it
打垮我
his personal mission to break me.
那你就专心不要让他打垮
Then you make it your mission not to let him.
哈维  他可是冠名合伙人
Harvey, he's name partner.
我给你讲过健身房的故事吗
Did I ever tell you the story about the gym?
我现在可没心情听故事
I'm not really in the mood for a story right now.
那你无论如何都得听
Then you're going to hear it anyway.
我小时候  我父亲把我送去拳击夏令营
When I was a kid, my father put me in boxing camp.
当时正值盛夏  三十多摄氏度
Middle of summer, 90 degrees.
每天做完拳击练习
Every day after sparring in that,
他们还会逼我们跑一百圈做五十个引体向上
they'd make you do 100 laps and 50 pull-ups.
他们会把我们逼到吐了或者晕倒
They'd push you until you either threw up
或者吐着晕倒
or passed out or both.
任何人都可以随时离开
Anyone could leave at any point.
只要说你放弃就行了
All you had to do was quit.
让我猜猜  你没有放弃
And let me guess, you didn't quit.
我每天都放弃
I quit every goddamn day.
但我从没有说出声
I just never said it out loud.
因为我才不会让他们
Because no way was I gonna give them
获得击垮我的快感
the satisfaction of breaking me.
所以现在轮到我放下身段任由路易摆布了
So I guess it's time for me to drop down and give Louis 20.
我估计他可不会给你好日子过  伙计
I think it's gonna be a little more than 20, buddy.
看来你注意到我把你的律师头衔刮掉了
I see you noticed I scraped your little associate title away.
是你刮掉的
You scraped it away?
是的  我会把你也给刮掉
Yeah, just like I'm gonna scrape you away,
从这些开始
starting with these.
路易  随便你
Oh, Louis, go ahead.
你可以把你能找到的最烂的案子都扔给我
Give me all of the shittiest cases that you can find,
但我告诉你
but I'm telling you,
这招打不垮我
it's not gonna break me.
你太高抬你自己了
You overestimate yourself.
我告诉你我要埋了你的时候
Did you think when I said I was going to bury you in shit,
你以为我是要用法律工作么
I meant legal work?
当然不是
No, no, no.
你不是律师
You're not a lawyer,
也就是说你只能做律师助理
which means you must be a paralegal,
所以你也就只配做律师助理的工作
and that's exactly the kind of work you're gonna be doing.
路易  你不能这样做
Louis, you can't do this.
外面每个人都认为我是律师
Everyone out there thinks of me as a lawyer.
两天前
And two days ago,
他们还以为我要走了呢
they thought of me as someone who used to work here.
可你看如今的情况
Look at us now.
而且如果你以为你可以去找哈维哭鼻子
Oh, and if you're thinking of crying to Harvey.
可就大错特错了
that would be a major mistake,
因为这是你和我之间的事
because this is between you and me.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我来是因为我知道你很生气
I'm here because I know you're angry
觉得自己被背叛了  但我不会让你
and you're feeling betrayed, but I am not gonna let you
就这样断绝我们的友谊
throw our friendship away.
我怎么可能断绝
I can't throw away something
从没存在过的东西
that never existed in the first place.
-路易  -唐娜  我们不是朋友
- Louis-- - Donna, we're not friends.
从来就不是  一切不过是一场谎言
We were never friends, because it was all based on a lie.
难道你觉得我送你这个
So you think my giving you this
为你做那么多事
and every other nice thing that I ever did for you
都只是为了防止你发现迈克的事吗
was just to keep you from finding out about Mike?
不  我没有这样想
No, I don't.
但我认为如果你有机会
But I do think if you had the chance
收回所有你为我做过的事
to take back all those nice things you did
来换取我永远不会发现你的小秘密
in exchange for me never finding out about your little secret,
你会眼睛都不眨就那样做
you'd do it in a heartbeat.
你想要有机会和我说实话
You want a chance to tell me the truth?
那就说吧  现在就和我说实话
Go ahead. Tell me the truth right now.
你的沉默就是答案了
And that answers my question.
你知道吗  路易
You know what, Louis?
这是个混蛋问题
It was a bullshit question
你是专门为了让我难受才说的
designed to do nothing but make me feel like shit.
我的目的达到了
Mission accomplished.
现在我对你重复我对迈克说过的话
And now I'm gonna tell you what I told Mike.
-你在我心目中已经死了  -好吧
- You're dead to me. - Okay.
你想恨我随你的便
You want to hate me? Hate me.
你想恨迈克也随你的便
You want to hate Mike? Hate Mike.
但这间律所不可能所有人在你心目中都死了
But everybody at this firm can't be dead to you,
因为早晚你会需要别人的帮助
because sooner or later, you're going to need someone.
谢谢你  唐娜
Thank you, Donna,
反正我不会需要你的帮助
but that someone isn't going to be you.
唐娜说你想见我
Donna said you wanted to see me.
不  我不是想见你
No, I didn't want to see you,
是需要见你
I needed to see you.
我知道你现在压力很大
I know you're under a lot of stress,
但我们不能再在这里那个了
but that was a one-time thing.
我不需要你帮我消耗精力
I don't need you to do that to me.
路易已经把我整够惨了
Louis has already done it.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
看看这个
Look at this.
他砸给我一大堆律师助理的工作
He's buried me in paralegal work.
这太过分了  他不能这样对你
Okay, that's bullshit. He can't treat you like that.
瑞秋  我不在乎你怎样对待我  好吗
Rachel, I don't care how he treats me, all right?
我能忍受他  让他撒完气
I can take it until he gets over this.
可看看这些截止期限
But look at these deadlines.
没有你的帮助我根本不可能
There's no way I can get all of this work done
按时完成
on time without your help.
你需要我干什么都可以  可是  迈克
I will do whatever you need, but, Mike,
如果你不让他停手他是不可能撒完气的
he is not going to get over it until you make him get over it.
-瑞秋  拜托  -迈克
- Rachel, please-- - Mike.
我们在这里那件事的第二天
The day after what happened in here happened,
我甩了你
I shut you out.
可是一周后  你来到我门前
But then, a week later, you came to my door,
你说你不会不争取就轻易放弃
and you said you weren't gonna let me go without a fight.
那不一样
That is not the same.
我那时候是希望你爱上我
I wanted you to fall in love with me.
我当时已经爱上你了  这你很清楚
I was already in love with you, and you knew it.
是啊  可惜的是路易不管怎么样
Yeah, well, Louis is a lot of things,
可并不爱我
but he's not in love with me.
他曾经很爱你
He used to be.
你只是需要让他想起这一点
You just have to make him remember that.
好吧  可我们还是需要
Okay, the first thing we need to do
先完成这些工作
is finish all of this work.
好吧
Okay.
除非  你的提议还有效
Unless, of course, that offer still stands.
我不记得我说了什么提议
I don't recall making an offer.
你说我需要你干什么都可以
You did say whatever I need.
我不是那个意思
That's not what I meant.
然后你又说无论什么我都不许拒绝...
And then you said never take no for an answer, so...
把门锁上
Lock the doors.
-你是认真...  -接受才是正确答案
- Are you serious-- - Take yes for an answer.
我马上锁门
I'm locking the door.
路易  你电话里说很紧急
Louis, you sounded urgent on the phone.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
我告诉你发生什么事了
I'll tell you what's going on.
我重回皮尔逊-斯佩克特了
I'm back at Pearson Specter.
什么
What?
我不明白
I don't understand.
让我解释给你听
Let me explain it to you.
我刚刚成为了冠名合伙人
I just became name partner.
路易  这太棒了
Louis, this is amazing.
我真为你感到高兴
I'm so happy for you.
好  你可以继续为我高兴
Okay, well, you can keep being happy for me,
但你最好也为自己感到高兴
but you better start being happy for you,
因为我要雇你回来
because I'm bringing you back.
什么  我...
What? I--oh.
卡特里娜·阿曼达·班尼特
Katrina Amanda Bennett,
你愿意来给我做律师吗
will you be my associate?
路易·马洛·利特
Louis Marlowe Litt,
我愿意做你的律师
I will be your associate.
做回你的律师
Again.
你让我成为了这世界上最幸福的律师
You've just made me the happiest attorney on earth.
我们什么时候开始再续这段美好前缘
When do we consummate our new preexisting relationship?
等我的新职位一生效就开始
As soon as my new position is official.
等等  为什么还没有生效
Wait, why isn't it official?
我不能告诉你为什么
I can't tell you that.
路易  我还以为我已经证明自己值得信任了
Louis, I think I've more than proven you can trust me.
你开什么玩笑
Oh, are you kidding me?
你是我唯一信任的人
You're the only one I can trust.
不是因为那个  只是...
It's not that. It's just--
好吧  路易  你不用告诉我
Okay, Louis, you don't need to tell me.
但如果你不能告诉我  他们也不能公布
But if you won't tell me, and they won't tell the world,
那一定有事情不对劲
something's wrong.
卡特里娜  我自有分寸
Katrina, I know what I'm doing.
而杰西卡也自有分寸
And Jessica knows what she's doing,
她能把你玩弄在鼓掌之间
which is playing you for a fool.
哈维  我正想给你打电话
Harvey, I was just gonna call you.
不用你麻烦了
I'll save you the trouble.
我们让路易·利特回律所了
We're bringing Louis Litt back to the firm.
这改变不了什么
That doesn't matter.
因为我正要给你打电话告诉你
Because that call was to tell you
我决定雇佣他  所以你欠我的
I'm hiring him, and you owe me.
胡扯
Bullshit.
你说我撒谎吗
You calling me a liar?
我并没有说你
I'm not calling you anything,
但你这是在说外面的西尔维娅说谎
but you are calling Sylvia out there a liar.
不不  西尔维娅一个字都不会和你说的
Oh, no, no, Sylvia wouldn't tell you shit.
你错了
Wrong.
恭维一句她的头发
One compliment about her hair,
她就告诉了我  你一个小时前就拒绝了路易
and she told me you gave Louis the bad news an hour ago.
回见  罗伯特
See you around, Robert.
哈维  还有一件事
Harvey, one more thing.
你还是欠我一个人情
You do still owe me that favor.
你打的是什么算盘
What kind of math are you doing?
我说的是杰西卡·皮尔逊
The kind of math that says Jessica Pearson
重新雇佣路易·利特是个黑幕
hiring Louis Litt back adds up to shady.
如果你只有这点证据
If that's all you've got,
那每次我遭遇罢工你都能收集不少人情
you can collect your favor when the clock strikes kiss my ass,
因为合伙人从律所进进出出是常有的事
because partners leave firms and come back all the time.
也许吧  但他们的名字可上不了墙
Maybe, but they don't come back with their name on the wall.
看来他不应该告诉我
Ah, I'm guessing he wasn't supposed to tell me that.
可他说了
But he did,
而路易·利特可不是冠名合伙人的料
and Louis Litt is not name partner material,
这意味着他肯定有你的把柄
which means he must have something on you.
所以除非你想让我在城里
So unless you want me going around town
四处散播你的家门之丑
flapping my big mouth that something isn't right in your kitchen,
否则你在我需要时最好乖乖帮忙
you're gonna make good on that favor.
西尔维娅那不是说漏嘴  对吗
Sylvia didn't slip up at all, did she?
对  不是
No, she didn't.
你有你的得力助手  我有我的
You have your girl Friday; I have mine.
但你出去的时候还是可以告诉她
But you can still tell her how nice her hair looks
她的头发很美
on the way out.
我会找你的
I'll be in touch.
这就要放弃了吗
Oh, you're tapping out already?
我以为你挺有种的呢
I thought you'd have a lot more backbone than that.
我没有要放弃
I'm not tapping out.
我完成了全部工作
I finished all of the work...
我希望你一小时之前就完成的
Which I expected to be done an hour ago.
得了路易  你压根没想到我能完成
Come on, Louis, you didn't expect it to be done at all.
同样  你也没想到这个
Just like you didn't expect this.
什么鬼东西
What the hell is that?
礼品券
It's a gift certificate.
干什么  想贿赂我吗
What, are you trying to bribe me now?
不是贿赂  是提醒
It's not a bribe, it's a reminder.
你看  这是彼得的牛排馆的礼券
Look, the gift certificate is from Peter's Steak House,
是你和我一起救下的那家牛排馆
the place that you and I saved together.
我们救下它之后
And after we saved it,
你跟我说  我们有共同之处
you told me that we had something in common.
是  可我不在乎
Yeah, I don't give a shit.
你在乎
Yes, you do,
因为我们的共同之处就是
because what we had in common
对法律的热爱
was a love of the law.
你要我当你的律师时  就是这么说的
You told me that when you asked me to be your associate,
路易  我还是当初那个人
Louis, and I am still the same person.
如果我发现  跟我合得来的女人
And if I found out a woman I had something in common with
其实是个男人  我可不会再跟她约会
was actually a man, I wouldn't keep seeing her.
好吧  可那跟我的事并不完全一样
Okay, what I did is not at all the same thing.
没错  你更糟
No, it's worse.
你说你很爱法律
You say you love the law so much,
可你染指的所有案子都被玷污了
but every single case you've ever touched is tainted.
你一旦被揭穿  彼得牛排馆就得被铲平
So you get exposed, Peter's gets bulldozed.
如果你我没有联手
It wouldn't even be there to get bulldozed
牛排馆被铲平前就不存在了
if you and I hadn't worked together.
好吧聪明鬼  你想一起工作吗
All right, genius. You want to work together?
你很爱法律吗
You love the law so much?
你最好记住我办过的所有案子
You're gonna memorize every case that I've ever done.
-路易  -不  干活儿去
- Louis. - No, get to work,
用你非凡的记忆
and use that magnificent memory of yours
干点正经事
for something more than
别在这儿荒废人生
bullshitting your way through life.
我们有个麻烦
We have a problem.
除非是紧急事务  否则我没时间
Unless it's urgent, I don't have the time.
路易跟别人说了
Louis is telling people.
谁
What people?
目前为止是罗伯特·赞恩
For starters, Robert Zane.
路易居然会跟罗伯特·赞恩说话
Why the hell is Louis even talking to Robert Zane?
我们夺回回春制药之后我求他雇佣路易
I asked him to hire Louis after we took back VersaLife.
而你到现在才告诉我
And you didn't think to tell me that after last night?
那时我一直掌握着大局
I was handling it.
那我告诉你  你掌握得糟透了
From what I can tell, you handled it like shit.
这是我的错吗
So this is my fault?
反正肯定不是我的错
Well, it sure as hell isn't mine.
杰西卡
You know what, Jessica,
可不是我想解雇路易的
I'm not the one who wanted to fire Louis,
也不是我想霸占他的客户
and I'm not the one who wanted to deny him clients.
我解雇他是因为他作为律师表现不好
I did that because of his performance as an attorney.
而你这么多年跟他不和只为自己高兴
You antagonized him for years for your own pleasure.
别自欺欺人了
Tell yourself whatever you want.
你也欺负过他
You handed out your share of abuse.
你才不要自欺欺人了
Tell yourself whatever you want.
是你雇了一个骗子  给了路易筹码
You're the one who hired a fraud and gave Louis leverage.
我也跟你说过路易会得寸进尺的
And I told you Louis would get worse,
而你说我必须承受
and you said I had to take it.
我不在乎是谁的错
Well, I don't care whose fault it is,
他现在得寸进尺了  我不要承受这些
he is getting worse, and I'm not gonna take it.
你必须承受
Oh, yes, you are.
你不但要承受
You're going to take it,
还要微笑着承受
and you're gonna do it with a smile on your face
直到我说够了
until I say otherwise.
你要干什么
And what the hell are you gonna do?
我去收拾烂摊子  一劳永逸
I'm going to clean up this mess once and for all.
你说没有镶钻名片是什么意思
What do you mean, you don't have diamond-encrusted business cards?
好吧  象牙浮雕的呢
Fine, what about the embossed ivory?
很好  一万张要多少钱
Okay, great, well, how much would 10,000 of those run me?
钱不是问题
Money's no object.
什么  你疯了吗  我才不会付那么多钱
What, are you crazy? I'm not paying that much.
除非它有镶边
Unless it comes with a reach-around.
可是我还是不会付那么多钱
Which, by the way, I'm still not paying that much.
精英印刷个鬼
Elite Printing, my ass.
我给你一个简单的指令
I give you one simple instruction...
让你把嘴闭好  你连那个都做不到
to keep your mouth shut...and you couldn't even do that.
好吧  你跟诺玛预约过吗
Um, okay, did you make an appointment with Norma?
-约什么  -和我会见
- What? - To see me.
你跟我的秘书诺玛约了吗
Did you check with my secretary, Norma?
省省吧  路易  我没心情玩这个
Cut the shit, Louis. I'm not in the mood.
那就培养一下心情  因为我才是握着底牌的人
Well, get in the mood, because I hold all the cards.
这些底牌可以换来你的名字上墙
And those cards are getting you your name on the wall,
可你不能四处宣扬
but you need to keep this to yourself.
为什么
Why?
让你就能想办法搞倒我吗
So you can figure out a way to screw me?
我向你承诺过
I gave you my word.
我不想失礼  杰西卡  但你的承诺一分不值
Well, no disrespect, Jessica, but your word means shit.
所以如果你不想让我宣扬
So if you want me to stop telling people,
那你最好替我去宣扬
you better start telling people yourself.
我说过  适当的时候会的
I told you, in good time.
我也说过  爷等不了
And I just told you I don't give a shit.
所以我建议你召集高级合伙人会议
So I suggest you call a meeting with the senior partners.
高级合伙人会议是在每周四
Those meetings are on Thursdays.
今天就是周四
Well, consider today Thursday.
我说过  我得想想怎么说让人接受
I told you, I have yet to figure out how to sell it.
你想知道怎么说  我来告诉你怎么说
You want to sell it? I'll tell you how to sell it.
你和哈维一起说
You and Harvey do it together,
真心真意地说  现在马上去说
you do it like you mean it. And you do it now.
懂了吗  很好
Got it? Good.
我想你们都听说了
I'm sure you've all heard rumors
有关我们召集这次会议原因的流言
about why we called this meeting,
而有流言是因为好消息要保密总是很难
but that's because it's hard to keep good news quiet.
本周稍迟些  我们会正式宣布
We'll be making this official later this week
但在此我要宣布我们有了新的命名合伙人
but we're here to announce our newest name partner,
路易·利特
Louis Litt.
谢谢  杰西卡
Thank you, Jessica.
哈维
Harvey.
也许有人想知道事情的原委
Some of you may be wondering how this happened.
解释很简单
There's a simple explanation,
对我来说就是承认一些事  那就是...
and all it requires is for me to admit something.
我犯了个错误
I made a mistake.
我不该接受路易的辞呈
I never should have accepted Louis's resignation,
不只因为他很会赚钱
because not only is he a billing machine
还因为他是位出色的律师
and a damn good attorney,
他私下还数次帮助过我解决麻烦
he has personally gotten me out of more than one jam,
除了我的朋友路易·利特  我不愿别人的名字
and there's no one I'd rather have my name next to
摆在我的旁边
than my friend Louis Litt.
谢谢你  哈维
Thank you, Harvey.
虽然现在还是"非正式"的  可我已经觉得
Even though it's "Not official," I already feel like
我的名字镶在墙上和你们一样久了
my name's been up there as long as yours.
我也真心觉得
And I definitely feel like
我的名字会镶在墙上很久  很久
it's gonna be up there for a long, long time.
会开得真是有用啊
A lot of good that did.
就让路易在他的重要时刻耍混蛋吧
Leave it to Louis to take his big moment like a dick.
哈维  冷静
Harvey, calm down.
冷静
Calm down?
我所说的正是他期待的
I just did exactly what he wanted,
而他却表现得像个混蛋  还会继续混下去
and he acted like a dick, and he's not gonna stop.
他不会罢休是因为你没有做他期待的事
He's not gonna stop because you didn't do what he wanted.
杰西卡  我刚刚在全体合伙人面前
Jessica, I just got up there and kissed his ass
帮他卖乖
in front of the entire partnership
还得假装很乐意
and pretended to like it.
没错
Exactly.
假装
Pretended.
你想让我真心乐意不成
Oh, you want me to actually like it?
我要你让他感受到  自己被接受了
I want you to make him feel accepted.
杰西卡
Jessica.
哈维  路易想要的是被接受
Harvey, what Louis wants is to be accepted.
无论你是否喜欢
And like it or not,
他最想看到的是被你接受
the person he wants that from the most is you.
所以你去找他  要非常友好友好
So you're gonna go to him, you're gonna make nice,
这就是我们收拾烂摊子的方法
and that's how we're gonna put all of this to bed.
有人能解释刚才搞什么飞机吗
You want to tell me what the hell that was?
请允许我失陪一下
If you'll excuse me,
让杰西卡解释吧
I'm gonna let Jessica handle this conversation.
我要去死一死了
I have to go kill myself.
杰夫  现在不是时候
Jeff, I can't do this right now.
我应该预约个时间吗
Should I make an appointment?
因为合伙人也许相信了路易胜利回归
Because the partners may have bought that fairy tale
这种美丽童话
about Louis's triumphant return,
可我比他们了解的更多
but they don't know what I know.
你知道什么
What exactly is that?
我知道路易犯罪了
That Louis committed a crime,
随后在你要解雇他之前的五秒钟
and then he resigned five seconds
他辞了职
before you were about to fire him.
现在他不仅回来了  还成了冠名合伙人
And now he's not only back, he's name partner.
我重新考虑了
I reconsidered,
作为经营合伙人  我有权这么做
which, as managing partner, i am entitled to do.
作为一个有头脑的人
And as someone with a brain,
我有权就此认为路易掌握了你的把柄
I'm entitled to come to the conclusion that Louis has something on you.
杰夫  你说不希望我再骗你
Jeff, you said you didn't want me to lie to you anymore,
我也尽力不骗你
and I'm trying like hell not to.
你现在的作为跟骗我没两样
And that's the same thing as lying to me.
不  这不一样
No, it's not.
你真是一个该死的律师
Oh, you are one hell of a lawyer.
你也是  所以你才会在这里
So are you, which is why you're here.
我跟你坦白
So I'll come clean.
但我不能告诉你事情的真相
I can't tell you the truth about this,
目前我只能诚实至此了
and that's as honest as I can be with you right now.
你能接受吗
Can you handle that?
现在可以
I can handle it for now.
但我不能永远被蒙在鼓里
But I won't handle it forever.
路易  你在这里做什么
Louis, what are you doing here?
我发现到你还没恭喜我呢
I noticed you haven't congratulated me yet,
所以我想给你个机会补说一下
so I wanted to give you a chance to make up for it.
好吧  恭喜你  我们都为你高兴
Right, congratulations. We're all so happy for you.
这就是你要的吗
Is that what you wanted?
你似乎有点不真诚
Seemed a little disingenuous.
那我就实话实说了
Then let me be clear.
我一点也不为此高兴
I don't mean a word of it.
你真想用这种口气对冠名合伙人说话吗
You really want to talk that way to a new name partner?
你用这种口气对你说话
I'm talking to you that way
是因为你靠威胁把我爱的人关进监狱
because you threatened to throw the man that I love in jail
才成了冠名合伙人
to become that name partner.
所以  路易
So, you know what, Louis,
我真是抱歉没给你烤个蛋糕
I'm sorry that I didn't bake you a cake.
那真是糟糕
That's too bad.
你没给我什么礼物
You didn't do anything for me,
我却给你准备了
but I got something for you.
文件复审
Doc review.
整理成一式三份
Filings to be done in triplicate.
既然你喜欢律师助理的工作  我就让你做
Paralegal work, since you like doing it so much.
你知道我根本不爱做这些
You know I don't like doing it at all.
你帮你的男朋友做过啊
You helped your boyfriend with his work.
你觉得我会不知道吗
You didn't think I'd figure that out?
你知道  我不在乎
You know what? I don't care.
你没有权利管我
You have no authority over me.
我是哈维的初级律师
I'm Harvey's associate.
没错  但我管所有的初级律师
Yeah, but I run the associates.
所以  我也管得着你
Therefore, I run you.
我知道你在做什么
I know what you're doing.
但你知道你自己在做什么吗
But do you know what you're doing?
你不仅仅和一个骗子一起生活
Not only do you live with a fraud,
你还像他一样...
you're just like him--
假装自己是个律师
pretending to be a lawyer when you're not.
我才没有假装
I'm not pretending to be anything.
我在读法学院
I am in law school.
你真的能读完吗
Are you really gonna make it through?
你连法学院入学考试都是勉强通过
You could barely handle the LSATs.
根本上不了哈佛
You couldn't get into Harvard.
老实说  虽然你的男朋友是个骗子
As a matter of fact, your boyfriend may be a fraud,
但他作律师  比你这辈子能达到的程度都高
but he's a better lawyer than you'll ever be.
你根本不知道我做律师能到什么程度
You have no idea what kind of lawyer I'm gonna be.
是吗
Don't I?
你师从身边最好的骗子  瑞秋
You learned from the best liars around, Rachel
哈维  迈克
Harvey, Mike,
你的父亲
your father.
我当然知道你能到什么程度
Yeah, I know exactly the kind of lawyer you're gonna be.
但在那之前
But until that day,
你还是最适合做这种工作
this kind of work is all you're good for.
你喜欢吃腌过的肉
So you like marinated meat?
好吃
Oh, yum.
等等  你做哪种
Okay, wait, but which one do you make?
堪萨斯城风格还是孟菲斯特色
Kansas City or Memphis style?
说到肋排
Oh, hell, when it comes to ribs,
我变尽花样去做啊
I make 'em every which way I can.
我现在真的饿了
I am now officially starving.
-哈维  -请坐
- Harvey. - Please have a seat.
别让我的工作影响你的咖啡小聚
Don't let my law firm get in the way of your coffee klatch.
别别  别责怪唐娜
Oh, now, now, don't blame Donna here.
我告诉她我和你还有些没谈完的事
I told her you and I had some unfinished business.
是吗
Already?
什么  你又挑了什么制式化的案件给我
What, did you pick something out of your generic favor file?
我从来不做制式化的事
I've never done anything generic in my life.
这是特别为你定制的
This favor is tailor-made for you.
非常特别也非常个性
It's very specific and very personal.
我们与另外一家公司有点小争议
We're in a little dispute with another firm.
我需要你让他们别闹了
I need you to get them to back off of it.
为什么你不自己做呢
Why can't you do it yourself?
因为我不认识对方的律师
'Cause I don't know the lawyer on the other side.
你认识  祝你好运
You do. Good luck.
他在说什么
What the hell is he talking about?
-是斯科特  -见鬼
- It's Scottie. - Aw, shit.
我明白
I know.
斯科特不会帮我这个忙的
Scottie doesn't do favors like this,
我也没有什么筹码让她帮忙
and I don't have any leverage on her.
你有
Yeah, you do.
你只是不想用罢了
You're just not gonna like using it.
你在这里
Hey, there you are.
我刚背完了路易的所有案件
Look, I just finished memorizing all of Louis's cases,
我想可以让你...
and I had an idea I wanted to run by--
瑞秋  怎么了
Rachel, what happened?
没事
Nothing happened.
路易做什么了
What did Louis do?
没事
It's nothing.
他发现我帮你做事
He found out that I helped you,
现在他给我分配了律师助理的工作
and now he's giving me paralegal work,
我有点沮丧但没事
and I was a little upset, but now I'm okay.
你可不只是一点沮丧
You weren't just a little upset.
你刚才哭过
You were crying,
你不会为律师助理的工作而哭的
and a little paralegal work wouldn't do that.
这无关紧要
It is not important.
你知道吗  是我自找苦吃
And you know what? I had it coming.
你自找苦吃
You had it coming?
你怎么了...瑞秋  他做了什么
What are you-- Rachel, what did he do?
迈克  是我叫你与他和解
Mike, I was the one that told you to make up with him.
-瑞秋  -我帮了你做事
- Rachel. - I helped you with the work.
-他究竟做了什么  -你知道吗
- What did he do? - And you know what?
我骗他的次数不比你少
I lied to him as much as you did.
他做了什么
What did he do?
他没有对我做什么  是他说的话
It's not what he did, it's what he said.
他说了什么
What did he say?
迈克  我不是小女孩了
Mike, I'm a big girl,
我可以处理路易的事
and I can take care of Louis.
这不仅是你的事
This isn't about you,
还关系着我和他
this is about me and him,
我会让他记住的
and I'm gonna make him remember that.
你这该死的东西
You piece of shit.
你说这只是我和你之间的事
You said this was between me and you.
确实是我和你的事
It is between me and you.
不  当你找瑞秋麻烦
No, it stopped being between me and you
这事就不仅是我俩的事了
the second you went to Rachel.
你找她帮忙的那一刻
You put her between us
就把她拉进来了
the second you went to her to help you.
天啊  你疯了吗
God, are you insane?
瑞秋一向对你很好
Rachel has never been anything but kind to you.
我都算不过来
I can't even count the amount of times
她帮你说话的次数了
that she defended you.
现在她就想帮我一点忙
And now, she tries to help me just a little bit,
你就把她大卸八块
and you rip her to pieces.
不  我说的不是今天的事  骗子
No, that's not the help I'm talking about, fraud.
那你在说什么
Then what the hell are you talking about?
你找她帮你为你的身份圆谎
You went to her to help you lie to me about who you are,
她这个小狗腿就屁颠屁颠
and like the good little lackey that she is,
跑到我面前对我撒谎
she came to me and lied to my face.
她这么做是为了保护我  路易
She did it to protect me, Louis.
那敢情好
Well, good for you,
但我发现了这件事
but when I found out about it,
我觉得恶心透顶了
I felt like shit for the 180th time.
所以我就以彼之道还之彼身了
So I just went to her and did the same thing.
路易  我刚背完
You know, Louis, I've just been memorizing
你以前所有的辩词
all of your old arguments.
我本来打算试试在这里
I was actually gonna try and come in here
引用一些来改变你对我的印象
and use one of them to change your mind about me.
-没用的  -我知道
- It won't work. - Oh, I know.
因为我还是原来的那个我
Because while I am the same person that I was before,
而你却变了
you're not.
你没说错
You're right.
我不是原来那个我了
I'm not the same person.
我原来是个言出必行的人
I used to be a man of my word,
但你们这些人却让我懂得那没有意义
but you people taught me that doesn't mean a thing.
所以当我告诉你
So when I told you
这只是你和我的事  我骗了你
it was between me and you, I lied.
我发现了你的弱点
I found your weak spot,
你知道我打算怎么做吗
and you know what I'm gonna do?
我打算继续打击她
I'm gonna keep hammering on her
直到你崩溃
until you break.
杰西卡
Jessica.
拜托  这事能不能等等  我累坏了
Please, if it can wait, I've had a long day,
得回家休息
and I need to go home.
真糟糕
Too bad.
你留在这里
You're staying here
起草路易·利特的新合伙人协议
and drafting Louis Litt's new partnership agreement.
你现在也要落井下石了吗
So now you're piling on too now?
我没落井下石
I'm not piling on.
我给你这个是因为这活不能计费
I am giving you this because it's non-billable work
而且这件事也是因你而起
and the only reason it exists is because of you.
又来了
This again?
你说什么
Excuse me?
你听得很清楚
You heard me.
我以前看过这出戏
I've seen this movie before.
但它之所以重复在上演
And the reason it keeps rerunning
是因为每次我认为我摆脱你了
is because every time I think I'm done with you,
你和你的肮脏秘密就又冒出来
you and your dirty little secret rear your ugly heads.
你知道吗  杰西卡
You know what, Jessica?
我受够你
I have had it up to here
一直说这是我的肮脏秘密了
with you saying that this is my dirty little secret.
你刚发现这件事时就可以解雇我  但你没有
You could have fired me when you found out, and you didn't.
你没有  你决定让我留下来
No, you decided to keep me around
因为你更加想要
because you were more concerned
打倒丹尼尔·哈德曼延续你的权力
with beating Daniel Hardman and keeping your power.
之后你再一次选择让我留下
And then you kept me around
因为你不想失去哈维
because you didn't want to lose Harvey.
然后你想利用我的秘密牵制哈维
And then you wanted to use my secret to beat Harvey,
之后就是一次又一次的重复
and then again and again and again.
所以杰西卡  你能不能告诉我
So please, Jessica, why don't you tell me,
这件事什么时候才能成为你的肮脏秘密
when the hell does this become your dirty little secret?
这里有人了吗
This seat taken?
你好
Hi.
Hey.
鉴于你的信息写的很含蓄
Since your message was so cryptic,
我猜是关于公事的
I'm assuming this is about business.
我需要你帮忙
I need a favor.
斯科特
Hey, Scottie.
你还好吗
How are you?
你离开之后过得怎么样
How have you been since you left?
我听说你休息了一阵子
I heard that you took some time off.
你去哪里了
Where did you land?
我希望你能和罗伯特·赞恩和解
I need you to settle your case against Robert Zane.
我为什么要那么做
And why would I do that?
因为我欠他一个人情
Because I owe him one.
哈维  我刚刚在这家新公司落脚
Harvey, I'm just getting back on my feet at a new firm.
这个案子赢面很大
This case is winnable.
公司也知道这个情况因为我告诉他们了
The firm knows that it is because I told them it is.
我和解了  会看起来很糟
I settle, I look like shit.
我知道  但你曾经来找我
I know that, but you came to me once
让我放过福尔松食品公司
to take it easy on you with Folsom Foods--
因为你说过如果我遇到私事上的麻烦
Because you said if I was ever in trouble personally--
我确实遇到了私事上的麻烦
I am in trouble personally.
你和罗伯特·赞恩有什么私人恩怨
What the hell is personal about Robert Zane?
如果你不帮我
You don't do this for me,
赞恩就会知道迈克·罗斯的秘密
Zane's going to put it together about Mike Ross.
你这个自私的混蛋
You selfish son of a bitch.
你说你之所以告诉我这件事
You said you told me that
是因为你不想一直对自己爱的人撒谎
because you didn't want to keep lying to the people you love.
我确实不想
I didn't want to.
但你现在来找我  用我知道的事
And now you come to me trading on the fact that I know
来换取摆脱因你的自私和愚蠢才陷入的困境
to get you out of a jam for doing something stupid and selfish
而这个窘境还断送了
that drove a wedge between us
我们最初在一起的机会
before we ever even had a chance.
我告诉你了真相
I told you the truth.
但那时已经太迟了
After it was too late.
斯科特
Scottie.
我那么爱你
I loved you.
I loved you,
但你却让一些我绝不会讲出去的愚蠢秘密
and you let some stupid secret that I would never tell anyone
阻碍了我们的关系  因为你无法信任我
come between us because you couldn't trust me with it.
你说得对  斯科特
You're right, Scottie.
我确实没有立场求你帮忙
I don't have a leg to stand on.
但如果你不帮我  我就会有麻烦
But if you don't do this for me, I am in trouble.
我会提议和罗伯特·赞恩和解
I'm going to recommend we settle with Robert Zane.
谢谢你
Thank you.
但事先跟你说清楚
But to be clear,
你只能这样拜托我一次
you get to ask me this once.
我再也不想听到迈克·罗斯这个名字了
And I never want to hear the name Mike Ross again.
斯科特
Scottie--
就一次
Once.
皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特
你想要正式
You wanted it to be official.
如你所愿了  路易
There it is, Louis.
这就正式了
It's official.
所以就这样了
So that's it?
人们明早就会像往常一样走进来
People are just gonna walk in here tomorrow morning
有可能看到  有可能看不到
like it's any other day and see it or maybe not see it?
那你还想怎么样
What were you expecting?
一个庆典外加管乐队吗
A ceremony and a brass band?
那不是我们的风格
We don't do that.
我是冠名合伙人  我就要那样做
Well, I'm name partner, and I say we do now.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你听到了
You heard me.
我要公开有排场的庆祝
I want pomp and circumstance in the form of an unveiling.
我要回家了  路易
I'm going home, Louis.
我不会将今晚剩下的时间用来
I'm not spending the rest of the night
给大家发送邀请邮件的
emailing invitations to an unveiling.
你要回家了
You're going home?
那我自己给他们发
Well, then I'll send them out myself.
因为明天
Because tomorrow...
我就要那样做
this is happening.
下午四点整
4 P.M. sharp.
我四点有个会
I have a meeting at 4:00.
那就重新安排时间
Then reschedule it.
你不是想我重新安排时间
You don't want me to reschedule.
你想要的是确定自己配得上这一切
What you want is to know you've earned that.
我配得上
I have earned it,
但我希望你知道这一点
but I want you to know it.
好吧  这样说吧
Okay, here it is.
你的名字在上面是因为你找到了一个把柄
You got your name up there by finding leverage
并且用它威胁我做了一些
and using it to strong-arm me into doing something
我绝不会做的事情
that I never would have done.
听着  我了解你
See, I knew you--
让我说完
Let me finish.
这个举动太过无情
It was a stone-cold move,
而且这正是哈维会做的事
and it's exactly what Harvey would have done.
如果这还不能让你知道你配得上这一切
Now, if that doesn't tell you that you've earned it,
那我也不知道什么能了
then I don't know what will.
你还想让我把会议改期吗
You still want me to reschedule my meeting?
是的
Yes, I do.
好吧  我会去的
Fine. I'll be there.
你和哈维一起
You and Harvey.
当然了  路易
Of course, Louis.
我们是你的合伙人
We're your partners.
天哪  你看起来糟透了
Jesus, you look like shit.
发生了什么
What's going on?
为了给杰西卡起草路易的合伙人协议
Between drafting Louis's partnership agreement
同时忍受路易无休止的攻击
for Jessica and Louis's never-ending onslaught,
我一晚没睡
I didn't get any sleep.
那去洗把脸吧
Well, splash some water on your face,
因为我们还要装作很在意的
'cause we have to go to his debutante ball
去参加个名媛成年舞会
and look like we give a shit.
不  我不去
No. I'm not going.
什么叫你不去
What do you mean you're not going?
现在不是激怒他的时候
Now is not the time to poke the bear.
太迟了
It's too late.
他就是个混蛋
The bear is an asshole,
他也不只是在拿我撒气了
and he's not just taking it out on me anymore.
-他还在针对瑞秋  -什么
- He's taking it out on Rachel. - What?
是的  他讲的很清楚他找到了我的弱点
Yeah, he made it clear that he found the weak spot
这招对我很有效
that's going to get to me,
而且他会一直不断地施压
and he's gonna keep pressing it and pressing it
直到我受不了为止
until I can't take it anymore.
迈克  你不能再招惹他了
Mike, you are not ringing that bell.
你说的对  我是不能惹他
You're damn right I'm not ringing that bell.
但如果我必须去对那个混蛋举杯致敬
But if I have to go raise a glass to that son of a bitch,
我一定会把杯子敲在他脑袋上的
I'm gonna end up smashing it over his head.
跟我来
Come with me.
你想干什么
What are you going to do?
我受够了
Enough is enough.
哈维  你来的正好
Harvey. You're just in time.
杰西卡正带着合伙人协议过来呢
Jessica's on her way down with the partnership agreement.
你是来当见证人的吗
You here to be my witness?
他来是为了阻止我把你的脑袋扯下来
He's here to keep me from ripping your face off.
我懂了  既然大哥来了
Oh, I see. Now that big brother's here--
够了  别闹了
Okay, that's enough.
路易  你得到了想要的一切
Louis, you got everything you wanted,
你不应该再拿他出气了
and you are done taking it out on him,
因为不管你做什么  我都不会让他辞职的
because no matter what you do, I'm not letting him quit.
-那我就直接解雇他  -你不能
- Then I'll just fire him. - You can't.
我能  并且我会的
I can, and I will,
因为杰西卡宁愿让他被解雇
because Jessica would rather he be fired
也不愿让你们都进监狱
than you all go to jail.
没人要进监狱
No one's going to jail.
听到吗  她明白现在的状况
See? She knows what's what.
我签了协议  他就完蛋了
I sign the agreement, he's done,
然后我把卡特里娜带回来做我的律师
and then I bring Katrina back as my associate.
那不可能
And that's not going to happen.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
路易  你已经把你最后一个要求用在
Louis, I'm afraid you've made your last dictate to me
冠名合伙人上了
as name partner.
我不会让你把它从我这里夺走的
I'm not gonna let you take this away from me.
我没有要夺走你的任何东西
I'm not taking anything away from you.
你还是冠名合伙人
You are still name partner.
但你要先把这个签了
Right after you sign this.
我在你起草的版本上又加了一些东西
I added a little something extra after you finished drafting it.
这上写我是雇佣冒牌货的共谋者
This says I'm coconspirator to hiring a fraud.
你是的
You are.
成为冠名合伙人后
You became one
一旦你利用这件事  你就成了共谋者
the second you used him to get your name on the door.
我知道我不是真正的律师
I know I'm not a real lawyer,
但在我看来他是共谋者
but that sounds like he is to me.
我是律师
I am a real lawyer.
他就是共谋
He is.
我不签
I'm not signing it.
路易  事情是这样的
Louis, here's the thing.
我让你把这事告诉任何人
I told you not to tell anybody about this,
但你却跑去告诉了罗伯特·赞恩
and then you went and you shouted it to Robert Zane,
之后又强迫我告诉合伙人们
and then you made me tell the partners.
现状是  有上百人等着
And the capper is, there are about a hundred people
在你安排的揭幕式之后
waiting to greet you
来向你致意
after the unveiling you arranged,
但你不签字  那些就不会发生
which won't happen if you don't sign that.
我还是可以去报案
I could still go to the police.
你可以  但你不会去
Yeah, you could, but you won't.
因为你利用那个小秘密
'Cause you used that little secret
走到了今天这步
to get where you are right now.
那是你枪膛里唯一一颗子弹
It was the only bullet in your chamber,
而我要把你的枪拿走
and I am taking your gun away.
你给我下套
You set me up.
是你自己给自己下的套
You set yourself up,
就像你跟查尔斯·傅滋曼的交易一样
just like you did with Charles Forstman.
我从他那学到的
And what I learned from him
就是一旦你得到想要的东西
was once you get something that you want,
就会不记代价地保护它
you will do whatever it takes to keep it.
所以你何不赶紧签字
So why don't you go ahead and sign
我们就可以开始你该死的欢迎派对了
so we can get out to your goddamn party.
非常有意思的事
You know, it's funny.
我们从没有为更名而开过庆典
We've never had a ceremony when we've changed names before,
但路易·利特竟大胆地把大家召集起来了
but Louis Litt had the audacity to convene us all here today.
而事实证明
And as it turns out,
他作为冠名合伙人的第一个决定非常英明
his first decision as name partner is brilliant,
因为这样的庆典给了我们一个机会
because a ceremony like this gives us a chance
让我们重新审视我们的位置和前途
to reevaluate where we've been and where we're going.
也许你与同事意见不合
Perhaps you had a disagreement with a colleague,
或者你心里还想着别的事
or there's some other issue that's been on your mind.
但重点是  新的名字带来新的开始
The point is, with a new name comes a new beginning.
就我而言  我希望大家把这看成一个机会
For me, I'm hoping we can see this as a chance
把往事一笔勾销
to wipe the slate clean.
说到这
With that said,
敬我们最新的冠名合伙人吧  路易·利特
here's to our newest name partner, Louis Litt.
说得好
Nice speech.
但愿值得吧
Let's hope it takes.
还是有希望的
It's got a better chance of taking
毕竟你让他签了协议
now that you made him sign the agreement.
是这样
That it does.
说到这个
Speaking of which,
你什么时候想出协议的事的
when exactly did you know you were gonna do that?
大概在唐娜告诉我他知道之后15秒吧
about 15 seconds after Donna told me he knew.
你完全没觉得应该让我参与计划吗
And you didn't feel the need to bring me in on that plan?
我的感觉恰恰相反
I felt the exact opposite.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
哈维  路易想看你难过
Harvey, Louis wanted to see you suffer.
如果我告诉你  你就得装难过
If I had told you, you would have had to fake it,
但你演技太差了
and you're a shitty actor.
拜托  我能演
Excuse me, but I can act.
不  谁都觉得自己能演  哈维
No, everybody thinks they can act, Harvey.
但事实是  你只是长得好看
The fact of the matter is, well, you're just a pretty face.
你觉得我好看
You think I'm pretty?
是非常傻
Pretty stupid.
真不敢相信它真上去了
I can't believe it's actually up there.
这律所改名比普林斯[著名歌手]都频繁
This firm is changing names more than Prince.
谁
Who?
你开玩笑的  对吧
You're kidding, right?
《紫色雨》
Purple Rain.
《树莓贝雷》
Raspberry Beret.
我开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
我本来差点就要重新评估我们的关系了
I almost had to reevaluate our entire relationship.
在你要去为我打倒路易之后吗
After you were gonna go and beat Louis up for me?
我很怀疑
I doubt that.
迈克  谢谢你
Mike, thank you.
那只是应该的
It just seemed right.
毕竟你也为我正面面对路易了
After all, you stood up to Louis for me.
我差点被打
And I almost got pummeled for it.
那需要勇气
That took guts.
所以我爱你
And that's why I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我想告诉你  你说的对
I wanted to tell you that you were right.
是我雇了迈克  引发了这一切
I started this whole thing by hiring Mike.
是我的错
It's my fault.
谢谢你
Thank you.
但我知道这件事情很久了
But I've been on board long enough,
也该接受现实了
and it's time I accepted the fact
那也是我的秘密
that it's my secret too.
那我们接下来怎么办
So where do we go from here?
我们拼尽全力保住秘密
We fight like hell to protect it.
没有蛋糕吗
No cake?
你来做什么  杰西卡
What are you doing here, Jessica?
我知道你等解释已经等烦了
I know you're tired of waiting for an explanation,
所以来给你一个解释
so I'm here to give you one.
你给我过解释了
You've given me explanations before.
我要事实
I want the truth.
你准备好接受事实了吗
Are you ready for the truth?
因为事实可不好看
Because it's not pretty.
只有一个办法来确定
There's only one way to find out.
感觉是很久远的事了
It seems like forever ago,
但其实并没有太久
but it wasn't that long ago at all.
丹尼尔·哈德曼挪用律所资金
Daniel Hardman embezzled money from the firm,
我为他遮掩了
and I covered it up.
别想错
Now, make no mistake,
我找出了事实  对抗他
I found about it, I confronted him,
最终让他作出了偿还
and I eventually made him pay it all back.
但我确实遮掩了那事
But I did cover it up.
瞒着合伙人  警方  瞒着所有人
From the partners, from the police, from everyone.
我甚至修改了账目  隐藏了罪行
I even adjusted our books to hide the crime.
但路易对这些事像猎犬一样   他发现了
And being a bloodhound about these things, louis found out
利用它作筹码重新回来了
and used it as leverage to come back.
作为冠名合伙人
As name partner.
你之前为什么不能信任我  告诉我
Why couldn't you trust me with that before?
因为我不知道你会有什么反应
Because I didn't know how you'd react,
我不想冒失去...一切的风险
and I didn't want to risk losing everything I had.
杰西卡
Jessica,
我会帮你保密
your secret is safe with me.
你迟到了
You're late.
但我带了礼物来
But I come bearing gifts.
看着不像煎饼卷呀
That doesn't look like cannoli.
这比煎饼卷强多了  爸爸
It's better than cannoli, Dad.
这是你新初级律师的简历
It's the resume of your new associate.
如果这是哈维试图因我没雇路易
If this is Harvey's way of trying to make up for the fact
而要的补偿...
that I didn't hire Louis--
不是哈维给的  是我
This isn't from Harvey. It's from me.
你要为我做这个
And you're going to do this for me,
我也不会欠你情
and I am not going to owe you a thing.
哥大就是这么教你的吗
This is what they're teaching you at Columbia?
互相帮助这种事不是这么办的
Because that's not how favors work.
我知道该怎么办
I know how favors work.
你做了这事  某天会需要我做别的事
You do this, and then you want something from me someday.
但到时候你就会知道
But by then you're going to understand that right now
现在是我在帮你忙
I'm the one doing you a favor,
因为卡特里娜·班尼特是个超棒的律师
because Katrina Bennett is an amazing lawyer.
我之前对你的评价错了
I was wrong about you.
你不像你妈妈
You're not like your mother.
你像爸爸
You're like your father.
拜托
Come on.
-那很好  -那样很好
- Oh, that's good. - That was a good one.
是啊  很好
That was a good one.
说话跟我一样  好女儿
Sounds just like me, baby girl.
我骗到你了  对吗
I had you fooled, huh?
没错
You did.
我来给你演示一下律师怎么做饭吧
Now let me show you how a lawyer cooks.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我只是觉得你会需要这个
I just thought you'd want this.
合伙人给你留的
The associates saved it for you.
他们没留
No, they didn't.
是你给我留的
You saved it for me
因为你想重新假装是我的朋友
because you want to pretend to be my friend again.
路易  你没有听到杰西卡的发言吗
Louis, didn't you hear Jessica's speech?
这是我们把往事一笔勾销的机会
This is our chance wipe the slate clean.
我听了
I did hear her speech,
我还知道是她派你来跟我说这些的
and I know that she sent you here to say that to me.
没人派我来
No one sent me here.
我来是因为自己想来
I'm here because I want to be here.
你看  话很好听
You see, that's sweet.
但我怎么能相信你呢
But how can I ever believe a word you say?
我想知道你有没有考虑过
I want to know if you ever thought once
告诉我迈克的真相
to tell me the truth about Mike.
没有
No, I didn't.
你当然没有
Of course you didn't.
-因为我们不是朋友  -你错了
- Because we're not friends. - You're wrong.
我们是朋友
We are friends,
但我对哈维的职业忠诚要高于友谊
but my professional loyalty to Harvey comes above that,
所以我没告诉过任何人
which is why I never told anyone--
杰西卡  瑞秋  任何人
Jessica, Rachel, anyone.
站在我的位置  问问你自己
So put yourself in my position and ask yourself,
你会怎么做
what you would have done?
我希望你告诉我点别的事
I want you to tell me something else.
好  什么事都行
Yes. Anything.
你跟哈维上过床吗
You ever sleep with Harvey?
等等  什么
Wait. What?
这不是职业问题
It's not a professional question.
是私人问题
It's a personal question.
你能给我们所谓的友谊足够高的地位
Can you put our so-called friendship high enough
诚实地回答它吗
to answer that one honestly?
-路易  -这是我能想到的唯一办法
- Louis-- - Because it's the only thing I can think of
来判断是不是能重新相信你了
to know if I can even begin to trust you again.
一次
Once.
那是我勾销往事的方法
That's my way of wiping the slate clean.
你接受与否都没关系了
You can accept it or not.